>> Jem Young: 我一直说港口和我之前应该定义的。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: And I keep saying ports and
I should have defined that earlier.
这是映射到特定进程或网络服务的通信端点。
It's a communication endpoint that maps
to a specific process or network service.
为什么港口呢 ?
Now what, so why ports?
在考虑操作系统级别时，为何需要端口
In terms of think about an operating
system level, why would I need a port for
什么
something?
>> Jem Young: 是的。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Yeah.
>> 演讲者 2: 就像在电视上换频道一样。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: It's like changing
the channel on your TV.
它使您能够以特定的通信方式进行拨号。
It lets you dial in a specific
mode of communication.
>> Jem Young: 是的。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Yeah.
> 演讲者 2: 让你的花生酱与巧克力分离。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: And let you keep your peanut
butter separate from your chocolate.
>> Jem Young: 花生酱和巧克力?
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Peanut butter and chocolate?
> 演讲者 2: 这是一个旧的 Reese 花生酱杯广告。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: It's an old Reese's
peanut butter cup commercial.
>> 演讲者 2: 但是的，关键是能够具体点，
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: But yeah,
the point is to be able to be specific,
跟你说的一个节目  还是什么的
to talk to one program that's talking to
you, FTP versus HTTP versus whatever.
>> Jem Young: 没错，在一台电脑上，我可以点击 IP 地址，
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Exactly, on a computer,
I can hit an IP address,
就像很酷
and it's like, cool.
我现在去哪
Where do I go now?
但是通过指定端口，
But by specifying the port,
我可以准确地说我想去哪里
I can say exactly where I want
this communication to go.
这比拥有万亿个 IP 地址的效率要高得多
This is much more efficient than having
a trillion IP addresses where every single
IP 地址是不同的服务。
IP address is a different service.
我们可以命中一个 IP 地址，并且具有不同的端口。
We can hit one IP address and
have different ports.
港口的危险之处在于，每个开放给互联网的港口
The dangerous thing about ports, is that,
every port that is open to the Internet
这意味着它很容易被利用
means it's a vulnerability,
potentially, that can be exploited.
因此，通常，您需要运行所需的最小端口数。
So in general, you want the minimum
amount of ports that you need running.
这就是为什么缺省情况下，端口会关闭，直到您打开这些端口为止。
That's why by default,
ports are closed until you open them up.
甚至现在我不希望港口 3000 的开放因为我不需要
And even now I don't want port 3000
open because I don't need that to be
暴露在互联网上
exposed to the Internet.
所以如果我去了，我刚才展示了这个。
So if I went to, and
I demonstrated this earlier.
这意味着我可以在 3000 口上最棒的
That means I can go to
jemisthebest on port 3000.
它仍然连接起来，这不是我们想要的。
And it still connects,
which is not what we want.
我们只需要 80 端口连接，所有流量都要经过端口 80。
We want only port 80 to connect, and
all traffic to go through port 80.
因为如果某个时间点我在 3000 端口上启动了另一个服务
Because what if at some point I started
up another service on port 3000, and
我重定向别处
I redirect somewhere else.
我现在有一个开放的港口，它很容易受到爆炸的影响。
I now have an open port that is vulnerable
to exploits or something like that.
因此，一般来说，端口的最佳实践总是使它们保持关闭状态。
So in general, the best practice for
ports is always to keep them closed.
除非您需要打开，并且只打开所需要的显式。
Unless you need to open up, and only
open up the explicit ones that you need.
因为再一次，扫描你需要花费很少的时间，
Because again, it takes a trivial
amount of time to port scan you, and
找出你正在运行什么软件什么是打开的
find out what software you're running and
what's open.
>> Jem Young: 如果我们想看到不同版本的端口，
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: And if we wanna see
a different version of the ports that are,
或者我们可以看到标准港口是什么
or we can see like what
the standard ports are.
他们可能大部分时间都不会开放
They're probably not gonna
be open most of the time.
但你可以少说 /etc/ 服务。
But you can say less /etc/ services.
我觉得这很有趣，另一个
And I find it really interesting,
cuz the other,
刚才我们谈到了标准港口的情况。
a bit earlier we talked about
how there are standard ports.
这就是为什么我们总是选择 2000 或 3000 或 1000以上的东西。
That's why we always choose something
above 2000 or 3000 or 1000.
因为有明确定义的端口，如 22。
Because there are well-defined ports,
like 22.
让我们看看这里 FTP 是 21 端口
Let's see what's on here, FTP is port 21.
这些只是事实上的标准，你可以随时改变这些标准。
And these are just de facto standards,
you can change these at any time.
但保留这些标准有时更好。
But it's sometimes better
to keep these standards.
前几天你说过
The other day, Sam, you mentioned,
如果您想的话，可以将您的端口从 22 更改为 " SSH " 。
you can change your port from 22 for
SSH if you wanted to.
你可以但这让 SSHing 有点棘手如果我想说
You could, but that makes SSHing it a
little bit more tricky if I want to, say,
跟你分享我的服务器
share my server with you.
但你绝对可以做到这一点，而且它只会改变港口地图。
But you can absolutely do that, and
it would just change the port map.
有没有关于港口的问题 ?
Is there any question about ports?
你唯一需要知道的是除非你需要他们，否则他们会关闭它们。
The only thing you really need to know is
keep them closed unless you need them.
如果你想给我太长的时间不听杰姆的
[LAUGH] Then if you wanna give a too long,
didn't listen to Jem.
好吧把他们关了
So yeah, just keep them closed.